{
    "id": "76758bf30d7d4c5d89ba1573ecf687a9",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Where ……………………… your father ……………………?",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to ask about people’s jobs. ",
            "answers": [
                "do, work",
                "does, work",
                "are, working"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My sister ………………………… plays for television.",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about people’s jobs.",
            "answers": [
                "write",
                "writes",
                "is writing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. anything this weekend?",
            "description": "We can use the present continuous to ask about arrangements.",
            "answers": [
                "Do you do",
                "Are you doing",
                "Will you doing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Call me when you ……………………. time.",
            "description": "In subordinate clauses we use a present tense to refer to the future.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "will have",
                "would have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Prices are ………………………… soon.",
            "description": "We do not normally use the present continuous to make predictions about events that are outside people’s control.",
            "answers": [
                "rising",
                "going to rise",
                "risen"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You will soon have an accident if you …………………………… on driving like that.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will go",
                "go",
                "goes"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………….. you a laptop for your birthday.",
            "description": "We use the simple future in promises.",
            "answers": [
                "will give",
                "would give",
                "give"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. we go out for a meal?",
            "description": "Questions with shall we or shall I are used to make suggestions.",
            "answers": [
                "Shall",
                "Will",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I will pay you back when I ……………………….. a job.",
            "description": "In subordinate clauses we use a present tense to refer to the future.",
            "answers": [
                "get",
                "will get",
                "would get"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We ………………………….. the work by Monday.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect to say that something will have been completed or finished by a certain time in the future.",
            "answers": [
                "will finish",
                "will be finishing",
                "will have finished"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I can’t play because I ……………………………. my leg.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to suggest that a finished action still has its effect in the present.",
            "answers": [
                "broke",
                "have broken",
                "had broken"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………. all my childhood in India.",
            "description": "We use the simple past to talk about longer situations.",
            "answers": [
                "spent",
                "am spending",
                "had spent"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}